Mss.B.G784
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], May 24, 1861; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Brandis, Dietrich, Sir, 1824-1907.
    Bonn, A.L.S. 1p. Introduces his brother, Dr. Bernhard Brandis.
  - Letter to Mrs. J. E. [Maria Emma] Gray, June 5, 1861; 7x4-1/2; Révy, J. J.
    London, A.L.S. 1p. Accepts invitation. Thinks her trial will take place next week.
  - Letter to Mrs. J.E. [Maria Emma] Gray, June 26, 1861; 8x5; Revy, J. J.
    Portsmouth, A.L.S. 1p. Accepts invitation if he is in London. Concerning his trial.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1861 July 21; Patterson, Robert, 1802-1872
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1862 January 27; Madge, Thomas
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1862 April 24; White, Walter
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1862 May 9; Jukes, J. Beete (Joseph Beete), 1811-1869
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1862 June 21; Tite?, N?
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1863 October 13; Wight, Robert
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1863 October 13
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1863 October 14; Kippist, Richard
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1863 October 27; Johnson, J.Y.
  - Letter to [Charles] Waterton, Oct. 28, 1863; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
    A.L.S. 3p. Expresses thanks for a photograph. Apologizes for delay in his reply.
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, 1864 January 1; Scharf, George, Sir
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, 1864 March 5; Colenso, John William, Bishop of Natal
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, 1864 March 6; Colenso, John William, Bishop of Natal
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1864 March 15; Goodwin, C.W.
  - Letter to "My dear Sir", 1864 April 7; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to General [Sir Edward] Sabine, April 23, 1864; 5-1/4x4; Christy, Henry, 1810-1865
    A.L.S. 4p. Concerning specimens from the far north.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, May 14, 1864; 7x4-1/4; Grove, George, Sir,, 1820-1900
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1864 May 17; Houghton, W. A., publisher
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1864 June 19; Olsen, Peter Bleeker
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, Sept. 8, 1864; 7x4-1/2; Beck, Richard
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerning a spider.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Oct. 29, 1864; 7x4-1/2; Davy, John, 1790-1868
    A.L.S. 2p. Forwards photograph.
  - Letter to Dr Gray, 1864 November 8; Colenso, John William, Bishop of Natal
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Nov. 21, 1864; 7x4-1/4; Ellis, Henry, Sir, 1777-1869
    A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for note, but is not yet 87 years old.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Nov. 28, 1864; 7x4-1/2; Flower, Edward Fordham, 1805-1883
    A.L.S. 2p. Sends picture of self.
  - Letter to [John Edward] Gray, Dec. 20, 1864; 7x4-1/2; Jardine, William, Sir, 1800-1874
    Jardine Hall, A.L.S. 4p., add. Concerning algae.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Dec. 28, 1864; 7x4-1/2; Flower, William Henry, 1831-1899
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerning a whale skeleton.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1864 December 30; van Beneden, B.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Jan., 1865; 8x5; Maximilian, Prince of Wied, 1782-1867
    New Wied, A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for photograph. Praises his work.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1865? January 27; Darwin, Charles [Robert], 1809-1882.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1865 March 10; Morgan, Frederic
  - Letter John Edward Gray, 1865 March 31; Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1829-1913
  - Letter to [John] Edward Gray, April 1, 1865; 7x4-1/2; Galton, Francis, Sir, 1822-1911
    A.L.S. 1p. Is sorry he could not accept invitation.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1865 April 1; Pettigrew, James Bell
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, April 3, 1865; 5-1/4x3-1/2; Christy, Henry, 1810-1865
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1865 April 6; Kirk, John, -- Sir, -- 1824?-1904.
  - Letter to [John] Edward Gray, May 16, 1865; Babington, Charles Cardale, 1808-1895
  - Letter to Mr Beckett, 1865 June 9; Jukes, J. Beete (Joseph Beete), 1811-1869
  - Letter to Mr.and Mrs. Gray, June 20, 1865; 6x3-3/4; Hurst
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Aug. 16, 1865; 6-1/2x4-1/2; Dixon, William Hepworth, 1821-1879
    A.L.S. 1p. Asks a favor.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, Sept. 3, 1865; 4x4-1/2; Gutty, Margaret
    Pembroke, A.L.S. 4p. News of her travels and of mutual friends.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1865 September 29; Van der Hoeven, J.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Dec. 27, 1865; 8x5; Deiben, Gustave von
    Stockholm, A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for publication. Friendly letter. Sends favors for the family.
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, 1866 January 13; Tatum, T.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1866 January 21; Hunter, Mr
  - Letter to [Mrs. Maria Emma Gray], Jan. 25, 1866; 7x4-1/2; Dornville, W. Henry
    A.L.S. 1p. Forwards a letter which is to be read and returned.
  - Letter to Mrs. M[aria] E[mma] Gray, Jan. 31, 1866; 5x4-1/2; Skoldberg, Sven
  - Letter to "My Dear Fanny", 1866 February 24; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, March 9, 1866; 6-1/4x4; Cooke, Edward William, 1811-1880
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], March 12, 1866; 7x4-1/2; Farrar, Frederic W.
    Harrow, A.L.S. 3p. Hopes to build a museum of natural history for Harrow. Concerning seaweeds for Mrs. Gray. Concerning Galton.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, April 2, 1866; 6-3/4x4; Ellis, William, 1800-1881
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma Gray], April 14, 1866; 5-3/4x4-1/2; Wentworth, William C., 1793-1872
    A.L.S. 1p. Invites them for a visit.
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, 1866 May 4; Stanley, Capt.
  - Letter to Lady Maria Bovill, 1866 July 27; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1866 November 10; de Quatrefages, C.
  - Letter to John [E.] Gray, Nov. 27, 1866; 5x4; Bonomi, Joseph, 1796-1878
    A.L.S. 3p. Sends him information pertaining to an entomologist going to Egypt.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Dec. 22, 1866; 7x4-1/2; Dillon, Frank
    Kensington, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning mutual friends.
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, 1867 January 9; Ward, Nathaniel Bagshaw
  - Letter to the President and Vice Presidents of the Royal College of Surgeons, 1867 January 17; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Jan. 22, 1867; 6x4; Dixon, William Hepworth, 1821-1879
    A.L.S. 1p. Asks him to write on Joshua Alder.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Feb. 2, 1867; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Schultze, Max, 1825-1874
    Bonn, A.L.S. 2p. Concerning natural history specimens.
  - Letter to John E. Gray, Feb. 6, 1867; 7x4-1/2; DuChaillu, Paul Belloni, 1838-1903
    A.L.S. 3p. Concerning natural history.
  - Letter to the President of Royal College of Surgeons, 1867 February 9; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Feb. 12, 1867; 6-1/4x4-1/4; Ella, John, 1802-1888
    A.L.S. 2p. Forwards tickets and will visit and tell of his journeys.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1867 February 15; Murie, James
  - Letter to [William?] Baird, Feb. 22, 1869; 5-1/4x3-1/2; Burton, Isabel Arundell, Lady, 1831-1896
    A.L.S. 2p. Asks him to "chaff" Dr. Gray and say that the shells are a gift to the British museum.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, 1867 February 24; Phillips, John
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], April 21, 1869; 7x4-1/2; Campbell, George Douglas, Duke of Argyll, 1823-1900
    A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for the paper. He considers some of the arguments good.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, April 23, 1869; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Franks, Augustus Wollaston, Sir, 1826-1897
    A.L.S. 2p. Recommends a man to study osteological section of the museum.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1867 May 16; Sclater, Philip Lutley, 1829-1913
  - Letter to P. L. Sclater, 1867 May 17; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, June 9, 1869; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Allman, George James, 1812-1898
    A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for the medal.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, June 9, 1869; 7x4-1/2; Bleek, Wilhelm Heinrich Immanuel, 1827-1875
    Oxford, A.L.S. 3p. Is sorry they cannot visit.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], June 13, 1869; 7-1/2x5; Agassiz, Louis, 1807-1873
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. Introduces George Agassiz who was with him durning his expedition in the Gulf of Mexico. G. Agassiz is interested in natural history.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], June 13, 1870; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Dundas, David, Sir, 1799-1877
    Richmond, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Thanks for favor.
  - Letter to Mrs John Edward Gray, 1867 June 29; Vaun, W.J.W.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Oct. 28, 1870; 8-1/4x4-1/2; Airy, George Biddell, Sir, 1801-1892
    London, A.L.S. 1p., end. Will be delighted to show Dr. Pierce around.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Oct. 29, 1870; 4-3/4x7-3/4; Crouth, E. A.
    A.L.S. 2p. Fragment. Introduces a friend.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], June 19, 1871; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Duméril, André Marie Constant, 1774-1860
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. with pass to the museum d'Histoire Naturelle pasted on. In French. Concerning the cataloging of specimens of natural history.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, July 8, 1871; 8x5-1/2; Recluz
    A.L.S. 3p. In French. Concerning natural history.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Maria Emma Gray], Oct. 9, 1871; 5x4; Bonomi, Joseph, 1796-1878
    A.L.S. 4p. Thanks for sketches for dishes.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Dec. 29, 1871; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Muséum d'histoire naturelle (Bourges, France)
    Paris, L.S.: E. Chevruel, director and A.T. Brongniart, treasurer. 1p. In French. Forwards models.
  - Letter to "My dear Sir", 1872 January 3; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Jan. 11, 1872; 7-3/4x5; Foger, Charles
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p. Doesn't like Paris.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, 1872? February 4; Darwin, Charles [Robert], 1809-1882.
  - Letter to "Sir", 1872 December 13; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to [Mrs. Maria Emma Gray], Feb. 11, 1873; 7x4-1/2; Dickie, G[eorge], 1812-1882
    A.L.S. 3p. Does not need a collection of algae.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Grey[sic], May 17, 1873; 7x4-1/2; Colnaghi, Dominic Paul, 1790-1879
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerning his collection of drawings.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, July 7, 1873; 7x4-1/2; Franks, Augustus Wollaston, Sir, 1826-1897
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, Oct. 14, 1873; 6x4; Thistleton-Dyer, William Turner, Sir, 1843-1928
    A.L.S. 3p. Accepts invitation.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Maria Emma Smith Gray], June 18, 1874; 7x4-1/2; Donaldson, Thomas Leverton, 1795-1885
  - Letter to "Dear Carruthers", 1874 September 18; Gray, John Edward, 1800-1875
  - Letter to J. P. G. Smith, March 22, 1877; 9x7; British Museum
    Printed L. filled in in ms.S.: J. Winter Jones. 2p. Thanks for gifts of publications and shells collected by Mrs. Gray.
  - Letter to S. O. Gray, June 20, 1877; 9x7-1/2; Inchfield, Edwin
    A.L.S. 2p. Concerning business matters pertaining to the estate of J. E. Gray.
  - Letter to J. P. G. Smith, March 23, 1878; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Monckton, John B.
    A.L.S. 1p. Has forwarded his request so that the copy will be made as soon as possible.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 7x4-1/2; Adams, Arthur
    A.L.S. 1p. Cannot visit with him this evening.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, undated; 4-1/2x7-1/2; Aikin, Arthur, 1773-1854.
    A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Encloses a ticket for the performance.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, undated; 4-1/2x7; Alfonso
    A.L.S. 1p. Hopes he will be at the meeting.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Annest, Joseph Lee
    Wednesday
  - Letter to Mr. & Mrs. Gray, undated; 7x4-1/2; Ansted, David Thomas, 1814-1880.
    May 27
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, undated; 4-1/2x3-3/4; Aryas, Joyce French
    A.L.S. 1p. Authorizes purchase of an emu.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 6x4-1/2; Barker, L. C.
    A.L.S. 1p. Returns books.
    July 21
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma Gray], undated; 4-1/2x3-3/4; Barnwell, C. F.
    Monday evening. A.L.S. 1p. Refuses invitation.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Barronde, J.
    A.L.S. 2p. In French. Accepts invitation.
  - Letter to Joaquim Alphonso, London, undated; 5-1/4x4; Batan
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Concerning an exposition. Refers to J. E. Gray.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, undated; 7x4-1/2; Bell, Thomas, 1792-1880
    A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for his letter and publication.
    June 14
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, undated; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Bell, Thomas, 1792-1880
    A.L.S. 2p. Congratulates him on the ending of the affair.
    April 2
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Bentham, George, 1800-1884.
    A.L.S. 1p. and end. Asks to send a box with his baggage.
    September 30
  - Translation by Dr Birch-hieroglyph, undated
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, undated; 7x4-1/2; Blackwood, John, 1818-1879.
    Lambeth, A.L.S. 1p. Introduces a rector who wishes to see him on a matter connected with the museum.
    April 23
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, undated; 8x5-1/2; Blanchard, Emile
    A.L.S. 1p. Introduces a friend who wishes to study at the museum.
  - Letter to Dr. and Mrs. Gray, undated; 7x4-1/2; Bleek, Wilhelm, 1827-1875]
    A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p. He and Mrs. Bleek accept their invitation.
    June 2
  - Letter to J[ohn] T[homas) Smith, undated; 8x4-3/4; Blucher
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 8x5-1/4; Bouchard-Chantereaux, Nicolas Robert, 1802-1864
    Boulogne, A.L.S. 2p. In French. Asks for publications.
    February 27
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Bowman, William, Sir, 1816-1892
    Monday morning. A.L.S. 1p. Asks favor.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, undated; 7x4-1/2; Brandis, Dietrich, Sir, 1824-1907
    Wednesday. A.L.S. 2p. Cannot accept invitation.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Braybrooke, Richard Griffin, Baron, 1783-1858.
    A.L.S. 2p. Does not think the idea will work out, due to the diversity of the views of the members.
    January 9
  - Letter to Dr. Bees(?), undated; 2-1/4x4-1/2; Brodie, Benjamin, Sir, 1783-1862
    A.L.S. 1p. Fragment.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 7-3/4x5; Brookes, Joshua, 1761-1833.
    Tuesday morning. A.L.S. 1p. Would appreciate his calling.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, undated; 3-3/4x7; Boie, Friedrich, 1790-1871
    A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Concerning his family.
  - Letter to Ed[ward] Doubleday, undated; 3-3/4x4-1/2; Bois-Duval, Jean Alphonse, 1801-1879.
    A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p. Wishes to know what has happened to certain natural history specimens.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 5-1/4x3-1/4; Bonomi, Joseph, 1796-1878.
    A.L.S. 1p. Fragment. Concerning illustrations of Burton's.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 4-1/2x3-3/4; Bonomi, Joseph, 1796-1878.
    A.L.S. 1p. Was busy and could not visit him.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma Gray], undated; 7x4-1/2; Bossey, F.
    A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for favor. Will cast his vote however she wishes.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 8x4-3/4; Brandis, Dietrich, Sir, 1824-1907
    A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for his kindnesses while he was in London.
    November 12
  - Letter to Dr Gray, undated; Buckland, Frank
    October 29
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 7x4-1/2; Buckland, William, 1784-1856.
    Oxford, A.L.S. 1p. and part of add. Asks for address of Mr. Goodby.
    October 12
  - Letter to [John] Edward Gray, undated; Bulwer, James Tandy, Jr.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, undated; 7x4-1/2; Burton, Isabel, Lady, 1831-1896.
    Friday. A.L.S. 2p. Sorry neither she nor Captain Burton could be with them last night.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Burton, Isabel Arundell, Lady, 1831-1896
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 5-1/2x3-1/2; Burton, Richard Francis, Sir, 1821-1890.
    A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for the card. Is quite welcome to the specimens.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, undated; 5-1/4x3-1/2; Busk, George, 1807-1886
    March 14
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], Jan. 12, undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Callcott, Maria, Lady, 1785-1842
    A.L.S. 1p. Cannot visit the museum. Has ordered a history of Spain sent to him for the children.
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Callcott, Maria, Lady
    January 12
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, undated; 4-1/4x4; Carpenter, Margaret Sarah, 1793-1872
    Saturday morning. A.L.S. 2p. She may use their oven.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, undated; 4-1/4x3-1/2; Carpenter, Margaret Sarah, 1793-1872
    A.L.S. 2p. Wishes to show her pictures to them.
    April 3
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 7x4-1/2; Cary, Francis Stephen, 1808-1880.
    A.L.S. 1p. Aks for a ticket.
    June 9
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 7x4-1/2; Catlow, Agnes
    A.L.S. 4p. Thanks for publication. Concerning conchology.
    January 20
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 7x4-1/2; Cayley, Arthur, 1821-1895
    Thursday. A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for note.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 7-1/2x4-1/2; Chadwick, Edwin, Sir, 1800-1890.
    Friday morning. A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for favor.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, undated; 8x5; Children, John George, 1777-1852
    Sunday. A.L.S. 2p. Concerning the name of a species.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, undated; 5-1/4x4-1/2; Carlton, William
    A.L.S. 1p Thanks for favor. September 16
  - Memorandum, undated; 1-1/2x7; Cline, Henry, 1750-1827
    "The above is not the conversation which passed between Mr. Lord and myself." A.D.S. 1p.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, undated; 7x4-1/2; Cobbe, Frances Rower
    Monday. A.L.S. 4p. Asks him to forward a book on algae to a college. Cannot visit with them.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, undated; 7x4-1/2; Cobbe, Frances Rower
    Monday. A.L.S. 3p. Asks if Dr. Gray will show them the museum.
  - Pass to admit the bearers, undated; 3-3/4x4-1/2; Colborne, John, Sir, 1778-1863
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, undated; 7x4-1/2; Cooke, Edward William, 1755-1820.
    A.L.S. 1p. Will show pictures.
    March 23
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Corney, L.J.
    A.L.S. 2p. Asks questions.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 5x3-1/2; Crock, D. M.
    A.L.S. 1p. Sends fossils.
    November 4
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Cumming, James, 1777-1861
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 1p. Sends name of place where reservations are made.
    June 19
  - Letter to John Edward Gray, undated; Cuming, Hugh, 1791-1865
    Monday
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, undated; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Cureton, William, 1808-1864
    Wednesday. A.L.S. 2p. Is ill and probably will not be able to visit tomorrow.
  - Letter to Mr. & Mrs. Gray, undated; 3x4-1/2; Cureton, William, 1808-1864
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 6-1/2x4; Cuvier, Mme. Anne, baronne
    Paris, A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p. In French. Wishes him a bon vayage, since he must go to Versailles.
    November 5
  - Letter to J[ohn E.] Gray, undated; 7x4-1/2; Dinkel, Joseph
    London, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for his invitation and will bring drawings of fossils. Will send list off to Mr. Agassiz.
    February 28
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 7x4-1/4; Don, David, 1799-1841
    A.L.S. 1p. Asks to borrow a book.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 4-1/4x4-1/2; Dillwyn, Lewis Weston, 1778-1855
    Friday. A.L.S. 1p. Has bruised his heel and cannot see him tonight, but suggests breakfast in the morning.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Dixon, James, 1788-1871
    A.L.S. 4p. Hopes to join the Zoological society.
    June 15
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, undated; 7x4-1/4; Doubleday, Edward, 1811-1849
    Saturday. A.L.S. 1p. and add. Letter of sympathy.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, undated; 7x4-1/4; Doubleday, J.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, undated; 9-3/4x8-1/4; Duchenne, G.-B. (Guillaume-Benjamin), 1806-1875
    A.L.S. 4p. In French. Concerning natural history and museums in Paris.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Duncan, Philip Bury, 1772-1863
    A.L.S. 1p. Recommends an excellent botanist.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Duvancel, Sophie
    Monday, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Wishes her bon voyage.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 7x4-1/2; Eden, Charles, 1839-1900
    A.L.S. 2p. Will advance his nephew when possible.
    December 5
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, undated; 5-1/2x3-1/2; Ella, John, 1802-1888
    A.L.S. 1p. Asks him to come and hear a concert.
    March 15
  - Letter to Mrs Maria Emma Gray, undated; 5 x 4-1/2 A.L.S. 1p Forward item which might interest her; Ellen, Anna
    February 14
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 5-1/4x3-3/4; Essex, George Capel-Coningsby, Earl of, 1757-1839
    A.L.S. 1p. Will see the man at 10 o'clock.
    March 13
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, undated; 4x3-1/2; Eyton, W. H.
    Tuesday. A.L. in 3rd. P. 1p. Refuses invitation.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, undated; 4x3-1/2; Falconer, Randle Wilbraham, 1816-1881
    Oriental Club, L. in 3rd. P. 1p. Accepts invitation. May 15
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, undated; 4-1/2x4; Farmdale
    L. 2p. Sends sketches. Cannot see them.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 7x4-1/2; Farnborough, Charles Long, Baron, 1761-1838
    A.L.S. 1p. Forwards drawings.
    November 28
  - Letter to John Edward Gray?, undated; [Farnborough, Charles Long, Baron, 1761-1838
    December 6
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 7x4-1/2; Farrar, Frederic William, 1831-1903
    Harrow, A.L.S. 1p. Will forward lecture when published. Friendly letter.
    February 15
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, undated; 7x4-1/2; Farrar, Frederic William, 1831-1903
    Harrow, A.L.S. 3p. Thanks for gift.
    February 1
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Fellows, Charles, Sir, 1799-1860.
    November 2
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 5x3-1/2; Fergusson, James, 1808-1886
    December 8
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; Férussac, Andre-Etienne-Just-Paschal-Joseph-François d'Audebard, baron de, 1786-1836
    Thursday morning. A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Asks question on natural history.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, undated; 6x4; Flight, Walter, 1841-1885
    Wednesday. A.L.S. 2p. Must go to Westminster with Maskelyne to experiment on electric lights, therefore cannot accept invitation.
  - Letter to [John E.] Gray, undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Flower,William Henry, Sir, 1831-1899
    Thursday afternoon. A.L.S. 1p. Cannot see him Saturday, but suggests the following week.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, London, undated; 7-1/2x7; Forbes, Edward, 1815-1854
    Saturday. A.L.S. 1p. and add. Returns Hewitt Watson's note. Concerning maps.
  - Letter to John J. Bennett, undated; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Forbes, John, 1799-1823
    Woburn Abby, A.L.S. 2p. Cannot dine with the Linnean society.
    May 19
  - Receipt to Mr. [John T.] Smith, undated; 2-1/4x6; Forshall, Josiah, 1795-1863
    A.D.S.: J. Forshall and H. H. Baber. 1p.
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, undated; 6-1/2x4-1/2; Forshall, Josiah, 1795-1863
    A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for gift.
    August 16
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, undated; 5x4; Fortune, Robert, 1813-1880
    Chelsea, A.L.S. 1p. Sends shells.
    May 28
  - Letter to J[ohn] E. Gray, undated; 7-3/4x5; Fortune, Robert, 1813-1880
    Chelsea, A.L.S. 2p. Sends skins of birds from China to the museum.
    April 16
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, undated; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Franklin, Jane Griffin, Lady, 1792-1875
    Monday. A.L.S. 2p. Sir John will dine with her if at all possible.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, undated; 4-1/4x3-1/2; Franklin, Jane Griffin, Lady, 1792-1875
    Tuesday morning. A.L.S. 2p. Will visit her Monday next.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, undated; 4-1/2x3-1/2; Franklin, Jane Griffin, Lady, 1792-1875
    Thursday evening. A.L.S. 1p. Asks when Sir John Richardson embarks.
  - Letter to [John E. Gray], undated; 9-1/2x7-3/4; Friend, Matthew Christey
    A.L.S. 1p. Asks them to postphone their visit, due to family illness.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, undated; 7x4-1/2; Gagliuffi, Mrs. Helen Dalzel
    November 6
  - Letter to Mrs. [Maria Emma] Gray, undated; 6x4; Gagliuffi, Mrs. Helen Dalzel
    Tuesday morning. A.L.S. 2p. Refuses invitation.
  - Card to J[ohn] E. Gray, undated; 3-1/2x4-3/4; Gervais, Paul, 1816-1879